# Vu Thanh Long

Date of birth: Oct 29, 1993

Gender: Male

Phone: +84 978389208

Email: wutianron@gmail.com

Address: Hanoi, Vietnam

Github: <a href="https://github.com/nhikhongkhong">https://github.com/nhikhongkhong</a>

Linkedin: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/vu-thanh-long-b6469b190/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/vu-thanh-long-b6469b190/</a>

Website: <a href="https://vu-thanh-long.herokuapp.com/">https://vu-thanh-long.herokuapp.com/</a>



### **OBJECTIVE**

Experienced Full Stack Developer with a demonstrated history of working in various industries. Skilled in Node, React, Typescript... Strong research professional with a Bachelor's degree focused in Computer Science from Murdoch University.

Fast learner, strong in Algorithms and Data structure. Works as full-stack developer, specialising in NodeJs, React. Proactive, enthusiastic, creative, humble, team player

### **EDUCATION**

Sep 2011 - Sep 2016 Hanoi University of Science and Technology

Majoring in Information System - HEDSPI Program

Sep 2018 - Mar 2020 Murdoch University (in Singapore)

 Bachelor in Business Information System (BIS) and Computer Science (<u>Academic certification</u>)

### **SKILLS**

Programming languages Javascript, Java, Node.js, Php, ReactJs, Typescript, Html5, Css, Web3 ...

**Database** MongoDB, MySql, Redis, Firebase, Graphq ...

Frameworks/Libraries Express.js, Et NextJs, React.js, Material-UI, Bootstrap, Ant Design, CSS/SCSS ...

**Tools** Office tools, git , visual studio code, figma ...

Language Fluent in English, Intermediate in Japanese (Equivalent to N3), Pre-Intermediate in

Chinese(HSK3)

Others

Have knowledge about Object Oriented Design, Data Structure and designing Database

### WORK EXPERIENCES

#### Apr 2021 - Present

#### **Vinox Software Solution**

Roles: Full-stack developer.

Main responsibilities:

- Coordinating with other teams (BA, Devops, development team) to improve the quality of products.
- Design new code base to reduce the cost and enhance the flexibility for adaptation based on express, nextjs, tailwind, graphql.
- Coding, bug fixing and code reviewing...
- Supporting team members.

#### Mar 2020 - Apr 2021

#### **Viettel Group**

Roles: BE developer, Software Developer.

Main responsibilities:

- Reconstructing software architecture.
- Project scheduling.
- System designing.
- Coordinating with other teams to improve the quality of products.
- Coding, bug fixing and code reviewing...

#### Sep 2016 - Sep 2018

#### Freelancer

Roles: Full-stack developer.

Main responsibilities:

- Build applications based on customer requirements.

### **PROJECTS**

### Centour Travel (Vinox Software Solution)

Project Type	Product
Customer	Centour Travel
Team size (man)	5
Descriptions	Centour Travel - a web-based system for online travel agencies that provides a wide range of travel services to their customers, including flight bookings, hotel reservations, tour packages, and visa applications. They carry out these services with the aim of providing convenient and affordable travel options to their customers.
My roles	Full Stack Developer
Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Involving in analysing customers requirements</li> <li>Developing front-end website architecture and code base for back-end system</li> <li>Design database schemas</li> <li>Create and execute unit tests and perform basic application testing</li> <li>Coordinating with other teams to improve the quality of products.</li> <li>Coding, bug fixing and code reviewing</li> </ul>
Technical in used	<ul> <li>Tailwind Css</li> <li>Databases(MySQL)</li> <li>Restful API.</li> <li>S3, SES.</li> <li>Docker, docker-compose, nginx, git, gitlab-runner</li> <li>NextJs</li> </ul>

## Soup Finance (Vinox Software Solution)

Project Type	Product
Customer	Soup Finance
Team size (man)	6
Descriptions	Soup Finance is a decentralised cross-chain money market for the metaverse economy. Supply crypto-assets to earn interest, and borrow assets for low interest subsidised loans with \$SOUP rewards
My roles	FE, Web3 Developer
Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Involving in analysing customers requirements</li> <li>Developing Website UI and UX</li> <li>Connect, interact with smart contract and integrate data on chain via rpc and metamask provider, using ether and web3.</li> <li>Create and execute unit tests and perform basic application testing</li> <li>Coordinating with other teams to improve the quality of products.</li> <li>Coding, bug fixing and code reviewing</li> </ul>
Technical in used	<ul> <li>ExpressJS, Node</li> <li>PM2, nginx, git, gitlab-runner</li> <li>NextJs, Tailwind Css, Figma</li> <li>Web3 react core</li> </ul>

## Worldmetasea (Vinox Software Solution)

Project Type	Product
Customer	Metasea
Team size (man)	6
Descriptions	MetaSea - The Amazing Adventure is a multiplayer building game where anyone can buy and own rare items, collect ancient sea monsters and meet new friends
My roles	FE, Web3 Developer
Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Involving in analysing customers requirements</li> <li>Developing Website UI and UX</li> <li>Connect, interact with smart contract and integrate data on chain via rpc and metamask provider, using ether and web3.</li> <li>Create and execute unit tests and perform basic application testing</li> <li>Coordinating with other teams to improve the quality of products.</li> <li>Coding, bug fixing and code reviewing</li> </ul>
Technical in used	<ul><li>ExpressJS, Telegraf.</li><li>Databases(MongoDb).</li><li>PM2, nginx, git, gitlab-runner</li></ul>

- NextJs, Tailwind Css - Web3 react core
--

## MangaM (Vinox Software Solution)

Project Type	Product
Customer	Manga M JSC
Team size (man)	6
Descriptions	A web-based system that allows the artists can publish their arts quickly, easily and at no cost.  The aim of this project was created solely to make meaningful and entertaining manga available for everyone regardless of their situations and locations. With the objective in mind, the team is to develop a user-friendly web application where any user is able to utilise it.
My roles	Full Stack Developer
Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Involving in analysing customers requirements</li> <li>Developing front-end website architecture and code base for back-end system</li> <li>Design database schemas</li> <li>Create and execute unit tests and perform basic application testing</li> <li>Coordinating with other teams to improve the quality of products.</li> <li>Coding, bug fixing and code reviewing</li> </ul>
Technical in used	<ul> <li>Adonis.</li> <li>Databases(MySQL), Redis.</li> <li>Restful API.</li> <li>S3, SES.</li> <li>Docker, docker-compose, nginx, git, gitlab-runner</li> <li>NextJs</li> <li>Redux</li> </ul>

## Viettel-Bamboo Airplane Ticket Booking (Viettel Group)

Project Type	Product
Customer	Viettel, Bamboo
Team size (man)	8
Descriptions	Bamboo Airways ticket booking on Viettel Platforms including web-app, My Viettel App
My roles	Back-End Developer
Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Involving in analysing customers requirements</li> <li>Analysing document and integrate API</li> <li>Design database schemas</li> <li>Design and integrate payment-gateway</li> </ul>

	<ul> <li>Create and execute unit tests and perform basic application testing</li> <li>Coordinating with other teams to improve the quality of products.</li> <li>Coding, bug fixing and code reviewing</li> </ul>
Technical in used	<ul> <li>Express, Restful API.</li> <li>Using Node.js to create HTTP server and using pm2 for process management.</li> <li>Databases(MySQL, Redis, Kafka).</li> <li>Logging and monitoring stack: ELK.</li> </ul>

### Viettel Core-Game (Viettel Group)

Project Type	Product
Customer	My Viettel App Users
Team size (man)	15
Descriptions	Series mini games on app My Viettel. Users play the mini game to receive free gifts including: data, free text-messages, minutes-call, vouchers for movie, grab, bbq
My roles	Back-End Developer
Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Involving in analysing customers requirements</li> <li>Read requirements and design the database and business.</li> <li>Design database schemas</li> <li>Design and develop Restful API for mini games, generate reports for administration</li> <li>Design and develop architecture for delivering-reward process</li> <li>Create and execute unit tests and perform basic application testing</li> <li>Coordinating with other teams to improve the quality of products.</li> <li>Coding, bug fixing and code reviewing</li> </ul>
Technical in used	<ul> <li>Express, Restful API.</li> <li>Using Node.js to create HTTP server and using pm2 for process management.</li> <li>Logging and monitoring stack: ELK.</li> <li>Databases(MySQL, Redis, Kafka).</li> </ul>

## Online Complaint Portal Management System (FYP)

Project Type	Prototype
Customer	Murdoch University
Team size (man)	7

Descriptions	A web-based system that allows the public, staff, students and anonymous personnel to file a complaint online. The complaint is allocated to an Investigator by the Administrator who manages the overall system.  The aim of this project is to reduce the time spent on the process of addressing issues and effectively rectifying the submitted problems by the complainants. At the same time improves the customer service of the organisation and customer satisfaction. With the objective in mind, the team is to develop a user-friendly complaint system where any user is able to utilise it.
My roles	Full Stack Developer
Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Involving in analysing customers requirements</li> <li>Developing front-end website architecture and code base for back-end system</li> <li>Design database schemas</li> <li>Create and execute unit tests and perform basic application testing</li> <li>Coordinating with other teams to improve the quality of products.</li> <li>Coding, bug fixing and code reviewing</li> </ul>
Technical in used	MERN stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js)     Server: Running virtual machine on provided Linux Server of Murdoch University
Additional Information	- Demo picture:  https://drive.google.com/file/d/16-R-TkIELIGRRX4_ObdAVCYyRq05uu8x/view?usp=sharing

## **INTERESTS**

I am a huge fan of Wuxia novels and traditional Japanese folk.

I also like playing Chinese chess on a regular basis, playing esports and have interest in in-house sports such as ping pong and basketball.